Guide to the Glasslands Gallery collection BCMS.0096
Brooklyn Collection
Glasslands Gallery collection
2010-2014
Brooklyn Collection
BCMS.0096
3.3 Linear feet in 2 oversize flat boxes
This collection consists of materials documenting the activities of Glasslands Gallery, a concert venue operating in Williamsburg from 2006-2015. Concert posters make up the bulk of this collection, featuring artists who performed at the venue from 2010-2014.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Audiovisual materials in this collection are unavailable due to technical limitations.
If digital surrogates exist, they should be used in place of the originals whenever possible.
The materials in this collection are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org at least two weeks prior to research visit.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Jake Rosenthal and Rami Haykal, 2015.
Related Materials
Brooklyn and Manhattan theater and concert programs scrapbook, 1977.205
Brooklyn and New York City musical performance scrapbook, 1978.061
Brooklyn Playbills and Programs Collection, BCMS.0041
Historical Note
Glasslands Gallery was a 300-person capacity concert venue operating from 2006-2015 at 289 Kent Avenue in Williamsburg, part of a converted warehouse complex. The venue was founded by musician Rolyn Hu and artist Brooke Baxter, co-founder of Glass House Gallery, an art gallery, community space, and concert venue located in the same warehouse complex. Glasslands used profits from early shows to slowly make improvements to the space, including a new sound system, a new toilet, and interior repairs. Hu and Baxter often used community members and friends to assist with upgrades and renovations. In addition to concerts, Glasslands featured a rotating selection of art installations, painting parties, and dinners. Early performances included local indie rock groups Vampire Weekend, Yeah Yeah Yeahs, and MGMT.
In 2008, events management and promotion collective Popgun Presents began to book events at Glasslands, creating a standing monthly show. In 2010, Hu and Baxter turned over all in-house bookings and programming decisions to Popgun, finally selling Glasslands to Popgun founders Jake Rosenthal and Rami Haykal in 2012. Rosenthal and Haykal increased show bookings and made several upgrades, including an improved sound system, updated bathrooms, and a coat check. In addition to indie rock groups, Glasslands also booked electronic, folk, hip-hop and heavy metal acts, frequently hosting DJ dance parties.
In 2014 several similar venues in the complex began to close in preparation for a conversion to office space for the broadcasting company Vice Media. On December 15, 2014, Glasslands announced its final show. The sold-out show was hosted on New Year's Eve with performances by Sky Ferreira, DIIV, Smith Westerns, and Beverly.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of materials documenting the activities of Glasslands Gallery, a concert venue operating from 2006-2015. Concert posters make up the bulk of this collection, featuring artists who performed at the venue from 2010-2014. Also included are two setlists, wristbands, tickets from a 2014 performance, an autographed vinyl record, and a small number of promotional materials. An Akai Professional APC40 controller used at Glasslands post-2009 is also included.
Concerts -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Bands (Music) -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Flyers (printed matter); Posters; Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.); Admission tickets; Performing arts festivals -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Musicians -- New York (State) -- Kings County
- Series 1: Ephemera
  - Concert Posters, 2010-2012 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Concert Posters, 2013-2014 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Oversize Concert Posters, 2013-2014 (Folder Flat File)
  - Setlists, 2014, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Tickets, wristbands, and promotional materials, 2014, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - T-shirt, circa 2014 (Box 1)
  - Guitar string, circa 2014 (Box 1)
- Series 2: Correspondence and Contact Information
  - Note and business card, circa 2013 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series 3: Audiovisual Materials
  - Mon Khmer vinyl record, 2014 (Box 1)
  - Akai Professional APC40 controller, circa 2009 (Box 2)